Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James.
And God spoke all these words saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above or that is in the earth beneath or
that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me. And showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy. Six days shalt thou labor and do
all thy work, but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work, thou, nor thy
son, nor thy daughter, thy manservant,
nor thy maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor
thy stranger that is within thy gates.
For in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea and all that in them is
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee.
Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt not
commit adultery. Thou shalt not steal.
Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbor's. I read Exodus 20:1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
Amen.
So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate. We are here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. But let me
introduce you the family that's on the
panel this evening. We got brother
Jerome.
Grace and peace.
Brother Julius. Good evening, everybody.
Brother Dre. Good evening.
Brother James.
Good evening, everyone.
Sister Deborah.
Good evening.
And we have sister Casey with us as well
as a guest caller and I'm brother
Cornell. Sister Deborah, what is our
first question of the evening?
Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So
Christie Watson says, 20 years and older
is the age of accountability, correct?
If is it so,
is so,
is safe to say 19 and younger will be in
the first resurrection?
All right, we talking about
accountability here, brother Julius. 20
verses 19.
Go ahead.
Is it the age of accountability?
Uh in most cases, yes, but it depends
upon the situation.
It depends upon the situation, sister,
because there are cases where
young children can get themselves hurt
for lack of understanding, lack of
knowledge, okay?
Now, let's answer this first question.
Um
20 years older and the age of
accountability, not necessarily. Let me
show you what the book say. Let's go to
Exodus the 20th chapter, James. Okay.
Exodus 20 and we going to read one verse
and then we going to go someplace else.
Exodus 20 and verse 12. What the book
say?
Honor thy father and thy mother, that
thy days may be long upon the land which
the Lord thy God giveth thee.
Honor thy father and thy mother that thy
days may be long
on which the Lord What if you dishonor
your mother and your father?
Let me give you a classic example.
Deuteronomy 21.
Mhm.
>> [clears throat]
>> Uh read verse 18 to 21. When you get it,
go ahead.
If a man have a stubborn and rebellious
son, which will not obey the voice of
his father or the voice of his mother,
Uh-huh. and that when they have
chastised him, will not hearken unto
them, then shall his father and his
mother lay hold on him. Uh-huh. And
bring him out unto the elders of his
city and unto the gate of his place.
Uh-huh. And they shall say unto the
elders of his city, this our son is
stubborn and rebellious. Uh-huh. He will
not obey our voice. Uh-huh.
>> a glutton and a drunkard. Uh-huh. And
all the men of his city shall stone him
with stones that he die. Uh-huh.
>> So shalt thou put evil away from among
you and all Israel shall hear and fear.
I don't think if you evil, you going to
go to the kingdom of God.
Let's go to one more place and I'll be
done.
One more place. Second Kings chapter 2.
See, it depend on your accountability
depend upon your behavior.
Not your not just your age, but your
behavior. Second Kings, James, chapter
2, read verses 23
to 24. This is in the day of the prophet
Elisha.
Second Kings 2:23 and 24. Go ahead.
And he went up from thence unto Bethel.
And as he was going up by the way, there
came forth little children out of the
city and mocked him and said unto him,
They came forth what now?
Came came up out of the city and mocked
him. Little children though, weren't it?
Yes. Go ahead.
And said unto him, go up, thou bald
head. Go up, thou bald head. Uh-huh. And
he turned back and looked on them and
cursed them in the name of the Lord.
Uh-huh.
>> And there came forth two she bears out
of the wood and tear 42 children of
them. So now, these are little children.
Mhm.
You mocking the prophet of God and you
think you going to go into the kingdom
of God in the first resurrection. It's
not happening.
It's not happening.
You know, you got to repent. But hey,
the book said that's the she bear tore
42 of them.
Killed them.
For mocking the servant of God. That's
the best I can do with that.
Anybody else?
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one. Mike Corley says, my wife is
asking if you can provide clarity on
being a talebearer.
She likes discussing matters that happen
at work.
All right. Clarity on being a
talebearer.
Brother Jerome.
Yeah, a talebearer is someone that uh
tells things about others,
you know, that can cause strife
between them
and their
friends or their family or their loved
ones or,
you know, acquaintances. You know, so
let's go to
some verses.
Let's go to Proverbs 11.
We going to read verse 13.
When you get it, go ahead and read it.
>> [snorts]
>> A talebearer revealeth secrets, but he
that is of a faithful spirit concealeth
the matter. Mhm.
And so those secrets and sometimes, you
know, you not helping the situation.
It's best to not say anything, you know.
Uh
but
>> [snorts]
>> go to Proverbs
16.
Okay.
And pick it up at verse 28.
A forward man soweth strife and a
whisperer separateth chief friends.
Yeah, see, and that's what a talebearer
often does. They try to do it when the
other person ain't around.
>> [laughter]
>> So they they they whispering,
you know, but these you can separate
chief friends by doing that.
Lord don't want us to do that cuz that's
talebearing. One more place. Proverbs 26
and verse 20.
Okay, 26 and 20 says,
"Where no wood is, there the fire goeth
out. So, where there is no talebearer,
the strife ceases." Yeah. So, he don't
want us to cause any strife. So, don't
be a talebearer. That That's all I got
on that. And sometimes sometimes brother
Jerome, you could tell the truth and
still be a talebearer. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yep. All right.
Thank you all for that. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one.
Next one, Kylie Parker asks, "If shaving
your beard is not a sin, did God put
that law because back then other nations
did it in honor of their gods? Is that
why God didn't want Israel to shave the
corners of their beard?"
All right, shaving your beard and was it
to another god? Guest caller.
Well, first thing is, you know,
when it come to sin, sin is the
transgression of the law.
And as far as other nations shaving
their beard,
there ain't nothing in the Bible that
talks about other nations shaving their
beard.
And if
shaving your beard was a sin, then
Joseph,
the guy that was second in charge of
Egypt,
the guy that taught the senators of
Egypt
wisdom,
sin.
And we didn't know And we didn't do that
because I knew Joseph would not commit
sin.
But look what he did. So, now, let's go
to Genesis 41 and read verse 14.
So, if shaving is sin, then Joseph is a
sinner.
And a lot of these people that make that
statement, I wonder if they ever
been
had the opportunity to be to run a
country big as Egypt.
Read it.
Genesis 41 and 14 says, "Then Pharaoh
sent and called Joseph. And they brought
him hastily out of the dungeon, and he
shaved himself
and changed his raiment and came in unto
Pharaoh."
Now, why would Joseph do that and the
Lord had been with him all the time? He
was sold by his own brothers.
And
and he got sold and he
become the top man in his master's
house. He become the top man in the
in prison. And when the master's wife
tried to get him to lay with her, he
wouldn't do it because he said he ain't
going to sin against God.
Now, if that's the case, then why would
he turn around and shave himself to go
before Pharaoh if it was a sin? Shaving
yourself is not a sin. And there ain't
nothing written in the King James Bible
that we use that says shaving is a sin.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on.
Moving on, Shanqula Kujobi wants
understanding
on Galatians 2 verse 16. He says someone
brought it to his attention after he
mentioned Deuteronomy 27 verse 10.
All right, brother Drake, can you shed a
little light on that Galatians 2 and 16
and then that Deuteronomy 27 and 10?
Let's Let's go to that Deuteronomy 27
and 10 first and just read that.
>> Read that when you get there, brother.
Okay. Deuteronomy 27 and 10 says, "Thou
shalt therefore obey the voice of the
Lord thy God and do his commandments and
his statutes, which I command thee this
day."
Ain't nothing wrong with that. Now,
let's go over to Galatians 2
and read what Paul said in Galatians 2
and verse 16.
Okay. It says Galatians 2 and 16.
It says,
"Knowing that a man is not justified by
the works of the law, but by the faith
of Jesus Christ.
Even we have believed in Jesus Christ
that we might be justified by the faith
of Christ and not by the works of the
law.
For by the works of the law shall no
flesh be justified."
So, what Paul is talking about here is
justification.
We are justified
by the blood of Jesus by faith in the
blood of Jesus. Does that mean that we
are not required to keep the
commandments of God?
Does that mean all we got to do is
believe? Let's go to somewhere else
where Paul said something about this
very thing. Let's go to Romans 2
and read verses 12 and 13.
Romans 2
12 and 13.
Go ahead and read it when you get there.
For as many as have sinned without law,
shall also perish without law.
And as many as have sinned in the law,
shall be judged by the law.
For the For not the hearers of the law
are just before God, but the doers of
the law shall be justified. So, now,
wait a minute. Paul is saying the doers
of the law shall be justified, not just
the hearers. And as many as have sinned
without law, they will perish without
law. And they will be judged by the law.
And many as have sinned in the law,
shall be judged by the law. Now, let's
go and read something Jesus said here.
Let's go to Matthew 19 and verse 17.
Read that when you get there, brother.
It says, "And he said unto him, Why
callest thou me good? There is none good
but one, that is God. But if thou will
enter into life, keep the commandments."
And that is that simple. Mhm.
That's that simple. That's what Jesus
said.
That's all I got. If anybody would like
to add.
Yes,
it's it's a place where you say that
somebody may find it said he will make
void the law through faith?
God forbid.
We establish it. Romans 3 and 31. Yes,
sir, Dre.
Romans 3 and 31 says, "Do we then make
void the law through faith? God forbid.
Yea, we establish the law."
Mhm. So, wait a minute. Back up. Back up
to verse 28 because you're talking about
justification. We justified by the blood
of Jesus, but that does not absolve us
from keeping the commandments. Go ahead,
brother.
Therefore, we conclude that a man is
justified by faith without the deeds of
the law. Yes, sir. Go ahead. Is he the
God of the Jews only? Is he not also of
the Gentiles? Yes, of the Gentiles also.
Mhm. Seeing it is one God which shall
justify the circumcision by faith and
uncircumcision through faith.
Do we then make void the law through
faith? God forbid. Yea, we establish the
law. See, Paul is telling you here that
we establish the law.
We don't do away with it because we
justified by faith. We establish it.
Thank you, guest caller.
All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
Next one, Charles Tumor says, "I noticed
that everyone has Bible study on
Wednesdays, people in the truth and
Sunday goers. Is there a reason why?"
All right, brother Drake, we are having
true Bible study tonight.
Hey, we have Bible study all the time.
In fact, you can go to YouTube and you
can see all of the different studies we
have on YouTube. We got the Balm of
Gilead. We got Brothers Working in the
Vineyard. We got the Coffee and Bible
Hour. We got Come On in My Room. We got
Let Us Reason Together. Line Upon Line.
Stick to the Script. Friday Night
Prayer.
Israel God on Clubhouse. We got Men of
God. We got Sabbath Day on Zoom. In
Atlanta, we got
IOG Teen Talk for Teens. We got plenty
of stuff. We got so much stuff, you can
study every day. Yes, sir. Now, let's go
over to
uh
Acts 17. Acts 17.
And I want you to read verses 10 and 11.
Acts 17 10 and 11.
Acts 17 verses 10 and 11 says, "And the
brethren immediately sent away Paul and
Silas by night unto Berea, who coming
thither went into the synagogue of the
Jews.
These were more noble than those in
Thessalonica and that they received the
word with all readiness of mind and
searched the scriptures daily whether
those things were so.
That's what we should be doing,
searching the scriptures daily.
Let's go over to one more place. Let's
go over to Hebrews 3 and 13. Read that
when you get there, brother. Hebrews 3
and 13 says, "But exhort one another
daily
while it is called today, least any of
you be hardened through the
deceitfulness of sin." Hey, daily we do
this. So, you just get online.
Sabbath day we got lessons. We Hey, you
could have lessons all the time.
The the wise
as it says in Psalm 1, they meditate on
the law day and night.
So, it's there for us. We just got to go
ahead and feed on it, eat on it. That's
all I got.
All right, brother. Thank you for that.
Hope that answered their question as we
move on to our next.
Next one, VinCam asked, "Who is the
woman to whom John wrote in 2 John 1
verse 1?"
2 John 1 and verse 1, who is this woman
mentioned?
Brother Julius.
>> [clears throat]
>> The church.
Yeah. The church. John is writing to
uh a group of churches and these are the
true churches of God.
These are the true churches of God and
everybody that's participating in the
true church of God. Pick it up.
2 John and verse 1.
And then we going to skip. I'mma show
you something here. Go ahead.
The elder unto the elect lady and her
children whom I love in the truth.
And not I only, but also all they that
have known the truth. And John did the
same thing that Peter did in 1 Peter the
5th chapter. John called himself an
elder and Peter was an elder and they
were elders of the church.
Skip down to verse 11. I'm sorry, skip
down to verse 12 and 13 to show you
uh in a dis- additional churches. Go
ahead.
Having many things to write unto you, I
would not write with paper and ink, but
I trust to come unto you and speak face
to face that our joy may be full. That
is called a church visit. Go ahead.
The children of thy elect sister greet
thee. Amen.
Because it was the different
metaphorically speaking, there were
different churches and the churches
always been called the woman. It's just
like Israel is called the woman. So,
this is metaphorically speaking, John is
writing to this the the true churches of
God in the areas that he traveled.
That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered
your
Uh move on. Moving on. D M Y C Witt
asked, "Does Hebrews 10 verse 26 mean
there is no more salvation or repentance
to those who backslide and have
persistent sin?"
Let's go there and read that.
Uh read the Hebrews 10
and let's read that 26 and 27.
And when you see the word willfully, you
sinning on purpose. You know it ain't
right, but you doing it anyway. You take
a big chance when you play that game.
Hebrews 10 and 26. Read 26
and then we going to read 27. Go ahead.
For if we sin willfully after that we
have received the knowledge of the
truth, there remaineth no more sacrifice
for sins. Right.
But a certain fearful looking for of
judgment and fiery indignation which
shall devour the adversaries.
Yeah, so
if you sinning willfully on purpose,
doing the things that you know that are
wrong and doing them anyway, hey, then
if you get caught up in it, then all you
got coming is verse 27. A certain
fearful looking for a fiery and
indignation which is the lake of fire.
But let's go into that uh Ezekiel 18
because all judgment is in the hand of
the Lord. So, we can't say that there
wouldn't be
no salvation or repentance. Repentance
is on that individual.
But let's go into Ezekiel 18. Read that
verse 23, brother, and then we going to
skip. Go ahead.
Have I any pleasure at all that the
wicked should die, saith the Lord God,
and not that he should return from his
ways and live?
Yes, because a living dog is better than
a dead lion. So, skip down to read 26
and 27.
When a righteous man turneth away from
his righteousness and committeth
iniquity and
dieth in them, for his iniquity that he
had done shall he die.
So, if you die in them, you know,
sometimes you can die doing that willful
sin and hey,
that's going to be held to your charge,
no doubt. Read 27.
Again, when the wicked man turneth away
from his wickedness that he hath
committed and doeth that which is lawful
and right, he shall save his soul alive.
So, hey, the Lord is merciful. Return
over to James, last place. James the 4th
chapter. James 4.
Cuz that willful sinning is nothing to
play with.
James 4 and read one verse for me,
brother. Verse 17. Go ahead.
Therefore, to him that knoweth to do
good and doeth it not, to him it is sin.
Yes, sir. So,
when you ask about that Hebrews 10 and
26, hey, don't be sinning on purpose.
You know it's wrong and you doing it
anyway, hey, let all your sins be on
accident because everybody got to appear
before the mercy seat of the Lord and
that's all I got.
All right. We hope that answered your
question and we going to move on to our
next.
Next one, Be Alert asked, "In Isaiah 14
verse 13,
Satan sits upon the mount of the
congregation.
Who or what is this congregation in
scriptures?"
Isaiah 14 and 13. Let's go there,
brother. Okay.
And when you get there, read it. They
want to know Satan sits upon the mount
of the congregation. Who is this?
Read and get scholar will take it from
there. Isaiah 14 and 13.
For thou has said in thine heart, "I
will ascend into heaven.
I will exalt my throne above the stars
of God.
I will sit also upon the mount of the
congregation in the sides of the north."
The first thing is
think up to 12 and then we going to
analyze this 13 verse. Read verse 12
first.
Verse 12 says,
"How How art thou fallen from heaven, O
Lucifer, son of the morning!
How art thou cut down to the ground,
which didst weaken the nations!"
For thou
Mhm. Now,
first thing is Lucifer, which ain't
Lucifer no more, but but that was
Satan's name before the Lord changed it
to Satan. Look,
he was thrown out of heaven.
And his biggest desire was to go back.
Read the next verse.
For thou has said in thine heart, "I
will ascend into the heaven. I will
exalt my throne
Notice, thou has said in thine heart,
"I will ascend into the heaven."
Now, finish it.
I will exalt my throne above the stars
of God.
Uh-huh. I will I will sit also upon the
mount of the congregation
in the sides of the north.
I will sit
He is not sitting there.
He was there in heaven and he got thrown
out.
And this and and where was that heaven?
That's That's
that Jerusalem.
That was new Jerusalem. In fact, the
earthly Jerusalem
uh uh
uh the the heavenly Jerusalem
is after is what is after what the
earthly Jerusalem was modeled on.
It's just like as it was they uh when
they built the tabernacle.
All of that was a duplicate of what's in
heaven.
Let's give you an example when he built
the tabernacle.
Go to Exodus 25th chapter
and read verse 9 and then skip down and
read verse 40.
Okay. Exodus 25 verse 9 says,
"According to all that I show thee,
after the pattern of the tabernacle, and
the pattern of all the instruments
thereof, even so shall ye make it.
Verse 40 Verse 40 says, "And look that
thou make them after their pattern,
which was shown thee in the mount."
You know, when Moses was up there, the
Lord showed him what was what what what
what was in the mountain.
So, he showed him the pattern that was
in heaven.
Now, read uh 26
and 30.
Exodus 26 and 30.
It says, "And thou shalt rear up the
tabernacle according to the fashion
thereof, which was showed thee in the
mount."
See?
Everything that we built was shown
in the mountain. Go to 1 Chronicles the
28th chapter.
Read verse
10 and skip down to 19.
1 Chronicles the 28th chapter, correct?
Mhm. Okay, and verse 10.
It says, "Take heed now, for the Lord
has chosen thee to build an house for
the sanctuary. Be strong and do it."
Skip down to verse 19.
"All this said David, the Lord made me
understand in writing by his hand upon
me, even all the works of this pattern."
See, so everything that was here, even
Jerusalem, was built on the pattern that
was in heaven.
And so uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh
Skip down to verse Let's go to Psalms,
brother, and read and read verse uh uh
uh uh Psalm the 48th chapter and read
verse two. 48 and two.
Psalms Psalm 48 and two says,
"Beautiful for situation, the joy of the
whole earth is Mount Zion on the sides
of the north,
the city of the great king."
So, that is talking about Jerusalem.
It was built on the same thing, a Mount
Zion, which is sides of the north. That
is the city of the king. That's where
Jesus is going to dwell. So,
Satan wanted to go back to heaven. He
don't want to come to this one. He wants
to go
to the one that's coming down. Let's go
to the last place, Revelation the 21st
chapter.
1 2 3 and we're going to skip down and
read verse 10 and 11.
Okay. Revelation 21 verses 1 through 3
say, "And I saw a new heaven and a new
earth, for the first heaven and the
first earth were passed away, and there
was no more sea.
And I saw John and I and I John saw the
holy city, New Jerusalem, coming down
from God out of heaven,
prepared as a bride adorned for her
husband.
And I heard a great voice out of heaven
saying, 'Behold, the tabernacle of God
is with men, and he will dwell with
them, and they shall be his people, and
God himself shall be with them and be
their God.'"
See, that is the Jerusalem that Satan
wanted to go to. Skip down to verse and
read verse 10 and 11.
Verse 10 says, "And he carried me away
in the spirit to a great and high
mountain, and showed me that great city,
the holy Jerusalem, descending out of
heaven from God,
having the glory of God, and her light
was like unto a stone most precious,
even like a jasper stone, clear as
crystal.
So, okay. Satan was in that Jerusalem
because he was in heaven.
But iniquity was found in him, and the
Lord threw him out.
And so, he swore that he going to go
above the clouds, he going to he going
to go
above God, he going to sit in the sides
of the mount.
Uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh
uh that city. What city? New Jerusalem.
But God in New Jerusalem is coming to
earth. So, Satan is not sitting nowhere.
That is where he want to go.
Like everybody that want to go to
heaven, that this is the one that they
are following. So, Satan is the only one
that said he was going back to heaven.
He going to go above the clouds. He
going to sit in the sides of the north.
Where is that? In New Jerusalem.
But he ain't going there, but the Lord
is going to bring that here. And when
the Lord bring it here, Satan will
already be in the lake of fire. That's
all I have to say.
All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered their question as we move on to
our next one with a time check.
Yes, the time is 8:05.
Michael Cross asks, "Were Nephilim
giants in Numbers 13:33?
And Genesis 6:4 says they were. And
Ephesians 6:10 says Goliath was a giant.
Was any after the flood?"
All right. So, what about these
Nephilims in Numbers 13, Genesis 6, and
Ephesians 6? Brother Julius.
All right. Uh the person is asking the
question and giving an and and then
turning around and giving me an answer.
Let's see if we can find Nephilims in
the KJV.
Genesis chapter 6. The Listen, sisters
and brothers.
You got that out of the Ethiopian Bible
and the Apocrypha that's listed in the
Ethiopian Bible.
Out of Out of the Apocrypha and out of
the Book of Enoch, I'm sorry. Out of the
Book of Enoch uh that's listed in the
Ethiopian Bible. There is no such thing
as a Nephilim
from Genesis to Revelation. Now, let's
look at what the Bible says. Genesis
chapter 6 and verse 1.
When you get it, James, go ahead and
read it.
And it came to pass when men began to
multiply on the face of the earth, and
daughters were born unto them. Uh-huh.
That looks
>> male and female procreating. So, we got
people being born. Go ahead.
that the sons of God saw the daughters
of men that they were fair, and they
took them wives of all which they chose.
These sons of God are the uh the uh uh
the sons of Adam and Seth.
And the daughters of men are are are are
the uh Cain's daughters, which were born
to him. Okay? After he was disinherited,
still male and female people that's
reproducing. Now, verse three, go ahead.
And the Lord said, "My spirit shall not
always strive with man, Uh-huh.
>> for that he also is flesh. Uh-huh.
>> Yet his day shall be 120
years."
>> I'm going to cut your years down because
of your sins. That's all this is saying.
Now, it's going somewhere else. Go
ahead.
"There were giants in the earth in those
days."
>> No, there were
No, there were definitely Nephilims.
"There were giants in the earth in those
days." So, it's now it's just telling
you there were giants in the earth, big,
tall people in the earth in those days.
Continue.
"And also after that, when the sons of
God came in unto the daughters of men,
and they bare children to them, the same
became mighty men which were of old, men
of renown." This scripture has nothing
to do with angels because angels do not
reproduce. They are spirit beings. So,
now, the Lord said these daughters of
Cain is going to turn to sons of God,
and they ain't going to follow me. Now,
let's go someplace else. Let's go to the
scripture that you said that you wanted
to go to. Let's go to Ephesians.
I'm sorry, Numbers. Numbers. Numbers,
James. Numbers chapter 1.
Numbers chapter 1, and when you get it,
my brother, please read.
Let me see here. Okay. Deuteronomy
chapter 1. Deuteronomy?
Yes. Okay, hold on.
>> My pages sticking together. Deuteronomy
chapter 1. And when you get it, read
verse 28. Moses is rehearsing Israel
history in the wilderness. Deuteronomy 1
and verse 28. Let's look at these
giants. Look Look what the what the
Bible called them, which were sons of
Hamites. Go ahead.
"Whither shall we Whither shall we go up
go up? Our brethren have discouraged our
heart, saying, The people is greater and
taller than we." Still people, not
angels. Greater and taller. You know,
like Shaquille O'Neal. Go ahead.
"The cities are great and walled up to
heaven. And moreover, we have seen the
sons of the Anakims there."
So, these are the sons of Anak.
Philistines' children, Hamites.
Deuteronomy chapter 2 and we're going to
read 10 and 11.
Um verse 9, let's get the background and
go ahead into it. We need to understand
this, y'all. Go ahead.
And the Lord said unto me, "Distrust not
the Moabites, neither contend with them
in battle. For I will not give thee of
their land for a possession. Because I
have given Ar unto the children of Lot
for a possession." Go ahead.
The Emims dwelt therein in times past.
Yes. A people great and many and tall as
the Anakims. Okay, they were Anakims and
they were people and big and tall.
What did they What did they call them?
Go ahead, verse 11.
Which also were accounted giants as the
Anakims, but the Moabites called them
Emims. That's why the book says in those
days there were giant people, big tall
people in the lands. That's all it said.
Now, let's go to the Yes, scripture that
you've given that you said that the book
of Ephesians chapter 6 says that there
are Nephilims in there. Let's see if we
can find it.
Ephesians chapter 6.
Because you're getting scriptures
crossed.
Ephesians chapter 6 is all about putting
on the armor of God, which is
metaphorically speaking uh things to
fight the devil with.
Now, have nothing to do with uh you can
read on your own. We're not We're not
going to read the whole thing. I just
want verse 10.
10 and 11, go ahead.
Finally, my brethren, be strong in the
Lord and the pow- and in the power of
his might. Uh-huh.
>> Put on Put on the whole armor of God
that he may be able to stand against the
wiles of the devil. And what is the
armor of God? Your faith. Your obedience
to the word of God. And in
metaphorically you read the whole
chapter, it'll tell you the armor, the
helmet, the sword. All these are things
that you use to go to war with because
you're in a spiritual war against Satan
and his minions.
That's what this is all about. Has
nothing to do with uh
uh
Nephilims.
Nothing.
So, therefore
that's all they are, big tall people,
giants, not Nephilims. The word Nephilim
is not in the KJV. It is in the
Ethiopian Bible. And people look at that
and then the Apocrypha and those are
myths, fables, and lies predicated off
the Bible. That's all I got. Uh yes,
Julius. So, uh scripture he gave was
Numbers 13 verse 33 about the Nephilim
being giants and Ephesians 6 that you
just finished. Right.
>> Uh he was talking about Goliath was a
giant. Yeah, Goliath was a giant. And
Goliath had a spear, a shield, and
armor. But Ephe- That's not in
Ephesians, the 6th chapter. Has nothing
to do with Goliath.
Right. Numbers the 13th chapter still
deal with the giants, big tall people
who had mothers and fathers. That's why
I said men began to multiply and
daughters were born to him and they had
children. And some children We still got
that today, big tall people. Look at
this guy that played for San Antonio,
Wembanyama.
Look at these guys, Shaquille O'Neal.
Look at these big tall 7-ft and 7-6 and
7-8 people, 7-ft 8. Goliath was 9-ft 9
tall. That's all.
That's all I got.
All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
their question. Next question, please.
Next one, Brick Brett asked, "Is 1
Timothy 3 verse 2 a good verse to prove
that only men can be pastors and not
women?"
Um that's one verse, but also we can go
to 1 Corinthians 14. But let's go and
read that verse they asked about, 1
Timothy 3 and 2, and then we'll open it
up to the panel. 1 Timothy 3 and
um
pick it up at verse 1 and 2.
Okay.
It says, "This is a true saying. If a
man desire the work of a bishop, his
des- he desireth a good work. Mhm.
>> A bishop then must be blameless, the
husband of one wife, diligent, sober, of
good behavior, given to hospitality,
apt to teach.
All right. So, you see there in that
first verse it said, "If a man" don't
mention anything about a woman in that
verse.
But uh let's go to 1 Corinthians 14 and
then let's open it up to the panel about
whether or not that only men can be
pastors and not women. 1 Corinthians 14
verse 33, brother.
Cuz the Lord set this in order himself.
Go ahead.
For God is not the author of confusion,
but of peace,
as in all churches of the saints. Mhm.
Let your women keep silence in the
churches. For it is not permitted unto
them to speak, but they are commanded to
be under obedience as also saith the
law.
Yeah, you can't be quiet and be a
preacher at the same time. Go ahead.
And if they will learn anything, let
them ask their husbands at home. For it
is a shame for women to speak in the
church.
Open to the panel.
Well, you already answered everything.
But read 1 Timothy 2 and 11.
1 Timothy 2 and 11.
Verse 1 Timothy 2 and 11 says, "Let Let
the woman learn in silence with all
subjection.
Finish it.
Verse 12 says, "But I suffer not a woman
to teach, nor to usurp authority over
the man, but to be in silence.
1 Timothy is telling you no, can no
woman be no pastor.
No.
That's the end of it.
All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question.
Next one, 52 Dad Do asked, "Is Russia,
China, and Iran in the Holy Bible? And
what role do they have in the future?"
Julius, is Russia, China, Iran in the
Bible? What is their role?
Number one, yes, they are in the Bible.
They are in the Bible and number two,
they play a major role in uh in the uh
in the Eastern biblical prophecy and
term and we're going to show you. Daniel
the 6th chapter, James.
Daniel 6.
I mean, it's all o- all in the early
books of Daniel.
All over Daniel.
Mhm.
Nebuchadnezzar's, Belshazzar's dream,
Nebuchadnezzar uh Nebuchadnezzar's
dream, but
you it's also in Daniel
uh 5
verse uh
28.
But Daniel's 6 and 1.
Daniel 6 and 1.
Go ahead when you get it.
It pleased Darius to set over the
kingdom 120 princes, which should be
over the whole kingdom. Uh-huh.
And over these three presidents, of whom
Daniel was first, that the princes might
give account unto them, and the king
should have no damage. Now, skip all the
way down to verse 7 because they tricked
uh Darius into signing the decree. Go
ahead.
All the presidents of the kingdom, the
governors, and the princes, and
counselors, and the captains have
consulted together to establish a royal
statute and to make a firm decree that
whosoever shall ask a petition of any
god or man for 30 days, save of thee, O
king, he shall be cast into the den of
lions. One more.
Now, O king, establish the decree and
sign the writing that it be not changed
according to the laws of the Medes and
Persians, which altereth not. Now, the
Medes are your today's Russia. Their
ancient name is Medes. Okay?
Another title, Meshech. But in 1929
she changed her name from Persia to
Iran.
So, you got your Russians and your
Iranians. That's why they are together
because they've always been together.
Okay? Now, you asked about China. Let's
find China in the Bible. Revelation the
16th chapter.
Because you got the the Western
alliances, which is your European Union,
all your Western countries, which does
not include the United States.
Western Europe. And then you have which
will be your 28 member nations and
finally will be 10 power nations. Now,
let's look at what the Bible called the
kings of the East.
Revelation 16, James, and read verse 12.
This is we're This is what we're waiting
on to see. East versus West and the Lord
going to dry up the Euphrates Euphrates
River right over there in the Middle
Middle East so that the kings of the
East, Russia, China, and Iran could come
through and the rest of their allies.
Verse 12. Go ahead.
And the sixth angel poured out his vial
upon the great river Euphrates. Yes.
>> And the water thereof was dried up. Yes.
>> way of the kings of the East might be
prepared. This is Russia, Iran, China,
Iraq,
India, North probably South Korea, but
all these having a line that have a
nonaggression treaty. So, this is the
kings of the East
that's going to come across the
Euphrates River to
to battle the Western European Union.
So, that's how they figure out in Bible
prophecy. We are waiting for this.
And it's going to happen. That's all I
got, brother Cornell.
All right. And thank you for that,
brother.
Thank you for that little history
lesson. All right. We'll go move on to
our next one. Hope that answer their
question, sister Deborah. Yes. Marquita
Gay asked, "If the Bible is not written
in chronological order, what is the best
way to read it to gain wisdom,
understanding, and knowledge?"
Well,
Marquita, one thing I've learned is to
read it from cover to cover.
Some people have never done that. Start
off in Genesis 1, read it all the way
down to Revelation 22. All 66 books.
It's good to read a book from cover to
cover and um but let's go into our
Ecclesiastes 12
because you asked about the wisdom,
understanding, and knowledge.
Because when you read it through, you're
not going to understand everything,
but this here is a big plus.
Ecclesiastes 12, brother.
And let's pick it up at that verse
nine. Ecclesiastes 12 and nine.
Go right ahead.
And moreover, because the preacher was
wise, he still taught the people
knowledge.
Yea, he gave good heed and sought out
and set in order many proverbs. So, once
you read this book and as you are
reading continually, you need to have a
preacher that understands and knows the
words of this book to be able to pass it
on to you cuz this word is given from
one shepherd. Verse 10.
The preacher sought to find out
acceptable words and that which was
written was upright, even words of
truth. And that which was written. Now,
that is my own personal opinion. Even
the words of truth. Verse 11.
The words of the wise are as goads and
as nails fastened by the master of
assemblies which are given from one
shepherd. All this word was given from
one shepherd. In Genesis 1 all the way
to Revelation 22. But then once you want
your wisdom, knowledge, and
understanding, you start to learn this
book and what it says. Read verse 13 and
14. This is your responsibility.
Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter.
Fear God and keep his commandments, for
this is the whole duty of man. And woman
and children. Go ahead.
For God shall bring every work into
judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil.
And that's all I got. Anybody else?
All right.
We're going to move on to our next
question, sister Deborah.
Yes. Jade Enduring asked, "Should I
return items given to me by someone I
found out that has poor money
management?"
Poor Poor money management. Should they
return the items that was given to them
by someone, guest caller?
That
is a decision you must make.
Mhm. All right.
We hope that that shed some light as we
move on to our next one.
Next one. Dad Two Step asked, "What does
it mean to use the Lord's name in vain?"
Using the Lord's name in vain, brother
Jerome.
It's
um to break his commandments. Especially
if you claiming to be his servant. Okay?
Um but let's look at some verses. Can we
go to Romans, the second chapter?
We're going to do Proverbs 32, um
James. We'll go to Romans, the second
chapter,
verse 23 and 24.
Okay. It says,
"Thou that makest thy boast of the law
through breaking the law
through breaking the law, dishonorest
thou God.
For the name of God is blasphemed among
the Gentiles through you, as it is
written." Yeah, so you're saying you
you're boasting about the commandments
and the law, but but through breaking
them, you're dishonoring the name of
God. Okay? But let's go to that Proverbs
30 and read verse nine.
Okay.
It says, "Lest I be full and deny thee
and say, 'Who is the Lord?' or lest I be
poor and steal and take the name of my
God in vain." Yeah, so you
if you're stealing, he's saying, "Lest I
steal." And he don't want to do it.
But he's showing you by doing it, you're
taking the name of the Lord in vain, you
know.
That's all I got on it.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we continue to move on to our next
one.
Next one. Jane Enduring asked, "What do
you do if someone is continuously trying
to keep you in a stronghold
or manipulate you into sin?"
All right. What do you do, brother Dre,
if someone's trying to manipulate you
into sin?
Let's go over to James, the first
chapter. James 1 and we going
read 13 through 15.
Read it when you get there, brother
James. James 1 verse 13 through 15 says,
"Let no man say when he is tempted, 'I
am tempted of God.'
For God cannot be tempted with evil,
neither tempted he any man.
But every man is tempted when he is
drawn away of his own lust and enticed.
Then, when lust has conceived, it
bringeth forth sin and sin, when it is
finished, bringeth forth death." So,
verse 14 says,
"Every man is tempted when he is drawn
away of his own lust and enticed." So,
we we're talking about
people coming to you with strongholds.
The first
person that you got to check is you.
Because if you checking you,
ain't nothing they can do to you. And if
you if you are weak when it comes to
that, then you got to pray about that.
Now, let's go to
uh
Second Corinthians,
the 10th chapter. Second Corinthians 10
and we going to read verses three
through five.
Second Corinthians 10 three through
five. Go ahead when you get there,
brother.
For though we walk in the flesh, we do
not war after the flesh.
For the weapons of our warfare warfare
are not carnal, but mighty through God
to the pulling down of strongholds.
Casting down all
That's the part right there. How you
pull down strongholds
is realize that your weapons are not
carnal,
but they strong through God and you got
to put on the word of God and apply it
to everything that's coming up against
you,
including strongholds.
But it starts with you. Verse five,
brother. Go ahead.
Casting down imaginations and every high
thing that exalteth itself against the
knowledge of God and bringing into
captivity every thought to the obedience
of Christ. Now, read one more Read that
next verse. Go ahead.
And having in a readiness to revenge all
disobedience when your obedience is
fulfilled. When your obedience is
fulfilled, you ready to revenge all
disobedience.
But you got to you got to cast down them
imaginations
coming at you and I'm not going to read
it, but I will say to you
on your read Ephesians 6 10 through 17.
And pray.
But then, put it on. Don't just pray
about it and if if if you dealing with
those things, I don't know where it's
coming from. You know. But if you in a
covenant relationship and you dealing
with it, it's not an excuse for you to
walk away. You got to stand in that
word. That's all I got.
All right. Thank you for that, brother.
Mhm. Did that answer their question as
we move on to our next one with a time
check? Yes, the time is 8:30. Lovely
Cole asks, "How do I repent? I really
want to get closer to God, but it's
hard. Any help?"
Well, first of all, when you repent, you
are sorry for the sin that you have
committed and that you're committing
against God. And so therefore, uh let's
go to Ezekiel 18. Ezekiel, the 18th
chapter.
Cuz when you asking Lord for forgiveness
for your sin, don't get up and go and do
the same thing
that got you in trouble in the first
place with God. Turn from those ways.
Well, let's go into Ezekiel 18.
And let's pick it up at that verse 30,
brother, when you get there. Ezekiel 18
and 30.
Go ahead.
Therefore, I will judge you, oh house of
Israel, everyone according to his ways,
saith the Lord God.
Repent and turn yourselves from all your
transgressions, so iniquity shall not be
your ruin.
So, repent and turn from the wrong that
you're doing, so that your sins will not
be your ruin.
Go ahead.
Cast away from you all your
transgressions, whereby ye have
transgressed.
And make you a new heart and a new
spirit. For why will ye die, oh house of
Israel? And the Lord say, cast away from
you all your transgressions, not some of
them, all of them that you have
transgressed and make a new heart that
you're going to serve God and keep his
commandments. For why will you die?
Verse 32.
For I have no pleasure in the death of
him that dieth, saith the Lord God.
Wherefore, turn yourselves and live ye.
Yes, once you putting yourself a new
heart, a new way of thinking, new way of
walking and not doing those sins that's
going to get you in trouble, hey, the
Lord say, turn yourselves so that you
may live. Now, turn over to Jeremiah 23
because you're saying it's hard. Now,
what's hard
is burning forever.
That is more than any person can ever
bear.
So, you do the commandments of God.
Jeremiah 23
and let's pick it up
at verse 33 and 34.
Go ahead.
And when this people, or the prophet, or
a priest shall ask thee saying, "What is
the burden of the Lord?"
Thou shalt then say unto them, "What
burden? I will even forsake you, saith
the Lord." So, even if you may feel that
way, change that way of thinking.
Keeping the law of God, hey, it's not
hard when you consider the consequences
and don't tell nobody else that. Verse
34.
And as for the prophet and the priest
and the people that shall say, "The
burden of the Lord, I will even punish
that man and his house."
So, delete that from your thoughts and
pick up your cross and serve God, keep
his commandments, so that you may live.
That's all I got.
All right, we hope that that answered
your question. We're going to move on to
our very next one, Sister Deborah. Yes,
Shammy uh wants you to explain Numbers
27 verses 15 through 18.
Moses asked to set a man over the
congregation.
Was this only during Moses'
disobedience,
or is this
a part of our custom today?
They say, "I know 1 Timothy 2 verses 11
and 12 says
says that, but I thought it was because
of sedition going on in the church."
All right, you got a little bit in this
question here, but let's go to that
Numbers 27
and pick it up at that verse 15.
And then the guest caller would take it
from there
about setting a man over the
congregation. Numbers 27 and beginning
at 15, brother.
Okay. It says, "And Moses spake unto the
Lord saying, Let the Lord, the God of
the spirits of all flesh, set a man over
the congregation."
Well, the first thing here,
uh Moses didn't have to take it to the
Lord.
Go over there and see where did the Lord
operate. The Lord set Moses over over
Israel.
Mhm.
That's the custom of the Lord. Set a man
over a nation, make him king
or either set a man over the church and
make him the pastor. That is the order
of God. The Lev- Levitical priesthood,
the Lord is the one that come up with
the Levite. So, when he uh uh and so
when he appointed the uh uh
Moses over Israel
and uh Aaron over the priests,
the order was set.
Got nothing to do with today, but it
flow but
it is an it is uh uh
it is
a pattern that the Lord set
not just today or yesterday, but over
all uh generations.
Now, for this this second part here,
you know, it's I I I want you to read
that uh uh uh
first but starting at the uh again,
where it said
uh I know it's 1 Timothy. Read it again.
All right, I know 1 Timothy
1 Timothy 2 verses 11 and 12 says says
that, but I thought it was because of
sedition going on in the church.
Now, you know, this is a question, but
I'm not going to lie to you.
This kind of offends me.
Say because of the read read it. Go
ahead and read it.
Okay. And that's that's 1 Timothy
1 Timothy
>> 11 and 12. Okay.
1 Timothy 2 11 and 12 says,
"Let the woman learn in silence with all
subjection.
But I suffer not a woman to teach, nor
to usurp authority over the man, but to
be in silence."
Now,
you going to say that this this is
sedition in the church? First thing is,
we'll go back to Aaron.
He was the high priest.
Every
priest after him was male.
Yep. Then under the new covenant, when
Jesus came,
he picked 12 apostles.
And when he got ready to get and and and
all of them was male.
And when he got ready to send an apostle
to
the Gentiles,
he picked another male.
Why?
It's because we saw illustration of it
in the Garden of Eden. Satan didn't
approach Adam because he know that it
wasn't going to wasn't Adam wasn't going
to deal with it. What did he do? He went
to the woman and approached her. Yes,
sir.
Now, I'm going to give you you know, to
show you this, I'm going to give you
something that nobody pays attention to
because do nobody read
uh uh
all of the Bible.
We're going to look at a woman that's
called Jezebel.
Okay?
Let's see who Jezebel
Jezebel was. Let's go into 1 Kings
the 16th chapter
and see what this woman cared about the
priests of God. Read from 30 to 32.
6- 1 Kings 16:30-32.
Okay. 1 Kings 16 and 30 to 32 says,
"And Ahab, the son of Omri, did evil in
the sight of the Lord above all that
were before him.
And it came and it came to pass, as if
it had been a light thing for him to
walk in the sins of Jeroboam, the son of
Nebat, that he took to wife Jezebel, the
daughter of Ethbaal, king of the
Zidonians, and went and served Baal and
worshipped him."
And he
Jezebel was the priest of Baal. So, when
he married this woman,
she started him to worshipping Baal. Go
ahead, finish that.
And he reared up an altar for Bale in
the house of Bale, which he had built in
Samaria.
Mhm.
Now, Jezebel caused that. I want to show
you something else that Jezebel did. Go
to 1 Kings 18.
Read verse 4
and then skip down and read verse 13.
Okay, verse 4 says, "For it was so, when
Jezebel cut off the prophets of the
Lord, that Obadiah took an hundred
prophets and hid them by 50 in a cave
and fed them with bread and water."
Now, Jezebel
cut off the prophets of God. He had over
400.
And this guy here that leads 100, skip
down to verse 13 and read it.
"Was it not told my lord what I did when
Jezebel slew the prophets of the Lord?
How I hid a hundred men of the Lord's
prophets by 50 in a cave and fed them
with bread and water?"
Now, this woman
she
represented a false god, Bale,
and she assaulted
God's prophet.
Go to 1 Kings 21 and read verse 23. I
want to show you something what God said
about this woman.
Uh 1 Kings 21 and 23 says, "And of
Jezebel also spake the Lord saying, 'The
dogs shall eat Jezebel by the wall of
Jezreel.'"
Now, God didn't even want her to have a
grave.
Go to 2 Kings
the ninth chapter and read verse 7.
2 Kings the ninth chapter
verse 7 says
"And thou shalt smite the house of Ahab
thy master, that I may avenge the blood
of my servants the prophets and the
blood of all the servants of the Lord at
the hand of Jezebel."
I mean, this woman
she was a servant of a false god and she
assaulted God's prophets.
Skip down to verse
31 and read to verse 37.
Verse 31 says, "And as Jehu entered in
at the gate, she said, 'Had Zimri peace,
who slew his master?'"
"And he lifted up his face to the window
and said, 'Who is on my side? Who?' And
there looked out to him two or three
eunuchs.
And he said, 'Throw her down.' So they
threw her down and sprinkled some of her
blood
and some of her blood was sprinkled on
the wall and on the horses, and he trod
her under foot.
And when he was come in, he did eat and
drink and said, 'Go, see now this cursed
woman and bury her, for she is a king's
daughter.'
And they went to bury her, but they
found no more of her than the skull and
the feet and the palms of her hands.
Wherefore they came again and told him,
and he said, 'This is the word of the
Lord, which he spake by his servant
Elijah the Tishbite saying, "In the
portion of Jezreel shall dogs eat the
flesh of Jezebel.
And the carcass of Jezebel shall be as
dung upon the face of the field in the
portion of Jezreel, so that they shall
not say, "This is Jezebel."
So, that's how the Lord felt about it.
Had her killed and then had dogs eat
her, so they wouldn't have no place for
the grave and say, "This is
Jezebel."
So, Jezebel was the priest of Bale.
And she
killed God's prophets. But look what
else. Let's go to this 1 Kings
18 and read verse 19.
1 Kings 18 and verse 19 says, "Now
therefore, send and gather to me all
Israel unto Mount Carmel and the
prophets of Bale, 450,
and the prophets of the groves, 400,
which eat at Jezebel's table."
Listen. So he wanted all of them
together so he could kill them all, but
whose table did these prophets of Bale
eat at?
Jezebel's.
Jezebel's table. Now, this is a woman
minister. Do you understand?
Mhm. So now, we're going to see what God
said
about
women ministers in the future.
Let's go to Revelation second chapter.
And we're going to read from 18 to 23.
Okay,
Revelation 2 verses 18 says, "Unto the
angel of the church in Thyatira write,
'These things saith the Lord of God who
hath his eyes like unto a flame of fire
and his feet are like fine brass.
I know thy works and charity and service
and faith and thy patience and thy works
and the last to be
more than the first.'"
He's talking to a church here. But go
ahead, and the last to be first. Go
ahead.
"Notwithstanding, I have a few things
against thee, because thou sufferest
that woman Jezebel, which calleth
herself a prophetess, to teach and to
deduce my servants to commit fornication
and to eat things sacrificed unto
idols."
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. This ain't
talking about Jezebel, Ahab's wife, cuz
she dead.
Mhm.
>> Dogs ate her.
So what we talking about here? These
churches are talking future here. Y'all
understand? Yes, sir. Mhm.
You don't see no individual woman that's
called Jezebel.
Because
if it was one, they'd give a name.
But not Jezebel. So Jezebel mean whoever
he said woman that suffered her to do
what?
Teach.
To teach.
Go ahead. And to seduce my servants.
Go ahead. Verse 21 says, "And I gave her
space to repent of her fornication, and
she repented not.
Behold, I will cast her into a bed and
them that commit adultery with her into
great tribulation, except they repent of
their deeds.
And I will And this ain't
This is not talking about a physical
fornication. This is a spiritual
fornication. Mhm.
Okay? This is metaphor letting you know
that if if you sitting under this woman
preacher and God say
didn't want that didn't didn't pick no
woman to preach, look what else he said
he's going to do. Go ahead and read.
Verse 23 says, "And I will kill her
children with death. And all the
churches shall know that I am he which
searcheth the reins and hearts, and I
will give unto everyone of you according
to your works."
Now, let's date this. Keep reading.
"But until you But unto you I say, and
unto the rest of Thyatira, as many as
have not this doctrine and which have
not known the depths of Satan, as they
speak, I will put upon you none other
burden."
Now, but I want to date it. Back up. Cuz
he said he's going to cast her into
what? Into great tribulation. Read that.
Verse 22, "Behold, I will cast her into
a bed and them that commit adultery with
her into great tribulation, except they
repent of her deeds."
Is it great tribulation here?
Nope, not yet. You don't see it here
yet?
Nope.
>> That's right.
That's That's the future. Start when
when you see the pope move into the
temple.
So this is not talking about any
individual woman. This is talking about
women, period.
And he used the most
notorious and cursed name among women
ministers
to identify them, and that is Jezebel.
So when you start talking about uh
talking about the the the the church
being
What does he say? Being
What is it? Chauvinist?
Sedition going on in the church.
So what's going on?
Sedition.
>> Sedition.
Right. That offends me.
And it should offend any servant that
know the word of God.
Show me one woman that wrote anything in
the Bible from Genesis to Revelation.
They've written about a woman. They've
written about what women did, like Ruth.
Like Queen Esther.
But it's the men
that the Lord set over the church. He
did it then. He did it while in the new
covenant.
And we are still are the new covenant.
Yes, sir.
>> So
system going out there, then remember
Jezebel and what the Lord said he going
to do with her and all of her children.
Those are the ones that are spiritual
children that follow and send under her.
Because Satan
got to Eve.
Satan got to Job's wife.
That's all I got to say.
All right.
Thank you for that as we move on to our
next question.
Next one, Philosophy asks, has Jeremiah
49:34
come to pass? A pastor spoke
spoke that the war with Iran is the
fulfilling of this prophecy.
Okay. Let's go to Jeremiah 49:34.
Jeremiah 49
Get there, brother. Read that verse 34
and then guest caller take it from
there. Okay.
The word of the Lord that came to
Jeremiah the prophet against Elam in the
beginning of the reign of Zedekiah, king
of Judah, saying,
I think they want 30 I think they want
34 to 39.
Okay.
>> Read 34. What does it say?
Again, 34 says, "The word of the Lord
that came to Jeremiah the prophet
against Elam in the beginning of the
reign of Zedekiah, king of Judah,
saying, Thus saith the Lord of hosts,
Behold, I will break the bow of Elam,
the chief of their might.
And upon Elam will I bring the four
winds from the four quarters of heaven,
and will scatter them toward all those
winds, and there shall be no nation
whither the outcast of Elam shall not
come.
For I will
Mhm. The first thing you need to just
need to re- re-
submit this question.
Because we ain't going to assume what
you trying to say.
But as far as this, you need to resubmit
this because what you gave don't have
nothing to do
with the in fact it don't have nothing
to do with no fulfillment of prophecy.
I need you to resubmit it.
>> All right. So
take out some time to resubmit your
question. Next question, Deb. All right.
He also said also asked
saying that I understand
that Isaiah 9:6 being the titles of
Jesus now. Thank you. However, could you
go Could you all go over in more depth
of why Jesus is our father? And why does
he tell us to pray to God the Father
even though Jesus is our father? I know
you all mentioned Exodus being the
adoption by Jesus, but what about other
scriptures
show that this was Jesus adopting Jacob?
All right.
I actually if you can please shorten
your questions for time's sake.
Um
Let's call her. Let's move quickly on
it.
We going to move quickly on this.
First thing is
Let's see
See Jesus
He have another name. Let's go and see
what the other name is called.
Let's go to Isaiah the 49th chapter.
Read verses 1 through 3
first.
Let me know when you finish three.
Okay. Isaiah 49:1-3
says, "Listen, all aisles, unto me, and
hearken ye people from afar. The Lord
hath called me from the womb, from the
bowels of my mother hath he made mention
of my name.
And he hath made my mouth like a sharp
sword. In the shadow of his hand hath he
hid me, and made me a polished shaft in
his quiver hath he hid me.
And said unto me, Thou art my servant, O
Israel, in whom I will be glorified."
That's the end of three.
He's not talking about the nation of
Israel. He's talking about Jesus. That's
one of his names. The reason I know,
look at
what this person said God has given him
another chance. Read verse six.
And he said, "It is a light thing that
thou shouldest be my servant to raise up
the tribes of Jacob, and to restore the
preserved of Israel. I will also give
thee for a light to the Gentiles, that
thou mayest be my salvation until the
end of the earth."
That let me know he's talking Jesus
here.
Jesus' name, one of his names also was
Israel.
And so
he adopted Israel. But let's go look at
and see when he adopted Israel. Let's go
quickly to Genesis the 32nd chapter.
Read verses 24 to 28. [clears throat]
This when
Jacob was left alone after he had sent
his family on ahead for fear of Esau.
Genesis 32
and
24,
sir?
Uh
listen. What did I say? Genesis uh
32.
Yeah, where Jacob wrestled. And 24 to
28.
Yeah.
Okay. It says, "And Jacob was left
alone, and there wrestled a man with him
unto the breaking of the day.
And when he saw that he prevailed not
against him, he touched the hollow of
his thigh, and the hollow of Jacob's
thigh was out of joint as he wrestled
with him.
And he said, Let me go, for the day
breaketh. And he said, I will not let
thee go, except thou bless me.
And he said unto him, What is thy name?
And he said, Jacob. And he said, Thy
name shall be called no more Jacob, but
Israel, for as a prince hast thou power
with God and with men, and hast
prevailed."
Now, that's when he adopted Jacob.
Go into Romans the 9th chapter and read
1 through 4.
Romans 9.
Romans 9:1-4
says,
"I say the truth in Christ, I lie not.
My conscience also bearing my bearing me
witness in the Holy Ghost, that I have
great heaviness and continual sorrow in
my heart.
For I could wish that myself were
accursed from Christ for my brethren, my
kinsmen according to the flesh, who are
Israelites, to whom pertaineth the
adoption, and the glory, and the
covenants, and the giving of the law,
and the service of God, and the
promises."
Now, he said, "Israel, to whom
pertaineth the adoption."
Do not. He adopted
Israel.
And when he adopted adopted Jacob, when
he gave So when he adopted Jacob, he
gave him his name, which is Israel.
And let's go and make sure that Israel
is his name. Let's go into 2nd
Chronicles the 7th chapter.
And read 12 through 14.
2nd Chronicles 7:12-14
say,
"And the Lord appeared to Solomon by
night, and said unto him, I have heard
thy prayer, and have chosen this place
to myself for an house of sacrifice.
If I shut up heaven, that there be no
rain, or if I command the locusts to
devour the land, or if I send pestilence
among thy people,
if my people, which are called by my
name, shall humble themselves, and pray,
and seek my face, and turn from their
wicked ways, then will I hear from
heaven, and will forgive their sin, and
will heal their land."
Now, he said, "My people, which are
called by my name." So what is the name
of his people? Israel.
That is God's name. He gave it to him
when he adopted him. So now,
[clears throat] that means that Jesus uh
and let you know that this that That's
when the Lord became the father to
Jesus, when he adopted him. Let me show
you that son to Jesus, brother.
That Jesus became Anyway, Jesus became
the father to Israel. How do I know?
All we got to do is find out who was
back there dealing with Israel.
So let's go into 1 Corinthians 10th
chapter and read verses 1 through 4.
1 Corinthians 10
verses 1 through 4 says, "Moreover,
brethren, I would not that ye should be
ignorant how that all our fathers were
under the cloud, and all passed through
the sea, and were all baptized unto
Moses in the cloud and in the sea, and
did all eat the same spiritual meat, and
did all drink the same spiritual drink.
For they drank of that spiritual rock
that followed them, and that rock was
Christ." Right. Okay. So Jesus was the
one that adopted Israel.
Jesus was the one that led Moses them
through the Red Sea.
Jesus was the one gave the commandment.
Mhm.
>> Jesus
is the only God that we have ever known
or dealt with.
So now,
therefore,
he was the one that adopted us, and he
is not the father, but he is our father.
Much more to that, but then we we can't
read the whole Bible to you. That's all
we have to say about that.
All right.
Hope you received that as we continue to
move on to another question.
Yes, NR says, "God commanded us to have
a holy convocation.
Does that mean just coming to Bible
study? My confusion is on holy
convocation versus convocation."
And they also ask
uh they want to know
want to know if I engage in conversation
about anything other than the word of
God on the Sabbath, have I polluted the
Sabbath?
All right, guest caller.
Yeah, well, you know, it look like
something else is mixed in the last
question.
Before we deal with this, let's back up
and read that. I knew you all you all
mentioned Exodus being adopted by Jesus.
Read that again. Then we get to this
this other one.
Okay. Uh so, you're going back to the
following question.
I missed it. What did it say? I knew
I know you all mentioned Exodus being
the adoption by Jesus, but what other
scriptures show that this was Jesus
adopting Jacob?
Okay, then.
Let's go to St. John the fifth chapter
and read verse 34.
John John 5
and
>> And 37.
John 5 and 34 says,
And 37. Oh, 5 and 37. And the Father
himself, which has sent me, has borne
witness of me. Ye have neither heard his
voice at any time nor seen his shape.
So, if you ain't never heard his voice
or seen his shape, then who was that
back there dealing with Israel? Jesus.
That was Jesus.
Therefore, he is
same thing. But now, he is he he is the
one that that
was adopted us. That's why he is called
our father, but he is not the father.
Now we can get to the other one.
Now, what do you say about God?
>> Yes, NR says, "God commanded us to have
a holy convocation.
Does this means just coming to Bible
study? My confusion is on holy
convocation versus convocation."
And he also wants to know if I engage in
conversation
during
about
>> If I engage in conversation about
anything other than the word of God on
the Sabbath, have I polluted the
Sabbath?
You know, uh you got too many questions
piled up in one from one person.
Yeah. Okay. We just talking about the
holy convocation first. Let's go to
Leviticus the 23rd chapter and read
verse 1 through 3.
Okay. Leviticus 23 verses 1 through 3
says, "And the Lord spake unto Moses,
saying, 'Speak unto the children of
Israel, and say unto them, concerning
the feast of the Lord, which you shall
proclaim to be holy convocations, even
these are my feasts.
Six days shall Mhm. Go ahead.
Six days shall work be done, but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of rest and
holy convocation. Ye shall do no work
therein. It is the Sabbath of the Lord
in all your dwellings.
Now, that holy convocation, that mean
the holy gathering.
That mean you got to come together. Go
to Isaiah 66 and read verse 23.
Isaiah 66 and verse 23 says,
"And it shall come to pass that from one
new moon to another, and from one
Sabbath to another, shall all flesh come
to worship before me, saith the Lord."
Now, come and and worship before, that
mean you got to come up and
have a holy gathering. Let's go to Acts
the 13th chapter.
1 and 3, then we're going to skip
14 and 15.
And then we're going to make another
skip.
So, that is Acts 13 verses 1 through 3,
correct?
Right, read that.
Now, there were in the church that was
at Antioch certain prophets and
teachers, as Barnabas and Simon that was
called Niger, and Lucius of Cyrene, and
Manaen, which had been brought up with
Herod the tetrarch, and Saul.
As they ministered to the Lord and
fasted, the Holy Ghost said, "Separate
me Barnabas and Saul for the work
whereunto I have called them."
And when they had fasted and prayed and
laid their hands on them, they were they
sent them away.
Now, skip down and read verses 14 and
15.
But when they departed from Perga, they
came to Antioch in Pisidia and went into
the synagogue on the Sabbath day and sat
down.
And after the reading of the law and the
prophets, the rulers of the synagogue
sent unto them, saying, "Ye men and
brethren, if ye have any word of
exhortation for the people, say on."
Now, they went into the synagogue on the
Sabbath day. Why? Cuz the people had a
holy convocation there.
And so, once they get through reading
the law and everything, they said told
Paul them, "If y'all got something to
say, say on. But we're not going to
concern ourselves with what Paul told.
We just concern ourselves with what
happened on the Pentecost." So, skip
down to on the on the Sabbath day,
rather.
Skip down to verse 42.
See what it say.
And when the Jews were gone out of the
synagogue, the Gentiles besought that
these words might be preached to them
the next Sabbath.
Now, the next Sabbath. How come they
could this could be preached to us
tomorrow?
Because the people come together on the
Sabbath.
But Paul ignored the Gentiles. Keep
reading.
Now, when the congregation was broken
up, many of the Jews and religious
proselytes followed Paul and Barnabas,
who speaking to them persuaded them to
continue in the grace of God.
And the
>> Mhm. It said when the congregation was
broken up, that mean when the meet was
over, ain't that right? Yes.
The holy convocation was over with, or
the solemn assembly.
Then
they was encouraging
Barnabas and Paul to continue, but
continue. Go ahead.
And the next Sabbath day came almost the
whole city together to hear the word of
God.
Now, how why is it
that they had to wait till the next
Sabbath day to come out to hear? It's
because the Lord told you to have a holy
convocation on the Sabbath day.
Now, let's go to Luke
fourth chapter.
And we're going to read verses 14
through 16.
Okay. It says, "And Jesus returned in
the power of the Spirit into Galilee,
and there went out a fame of him through
all the region round about.
And he taught in their synagogues, being
glorified of all.
And he came to Nazareth, where he had
been brought up, and as his custom was,
he went into the synagogue on the
Sabbath day and stood up for to read on
the Sabbath day."
On the Sabbath day. Mhm.
When he and when he got he got up and
read
and then he explained that they was
talking about him, then they wanted to
stone him. He had to walk through them.
But that's where he went But once he got
away from them, let's see what happened.
Skip down and read verse 31.
And came down to Capernaum, a city of
Galilee, and taught them on the Sabbath
days.
Now, why
was Jesus teaching them on the Sabbath
day? Because they was having a holy
convocation, a solemn assembly.
So, you're supposed to have a holy
convocation on the Sabbath day, not
sitting in your house looking at TV, and
you got a
congregation up the streets. That's all
I have to say.
But as far as this other
>> I got Well, but for this other part, it
it said
read that if
about engaging conversation.
Right. If I engage in conversation
about anything other than the word of
God on the Sabbath, have I polluted the
Sabbath?
It depends on what you're talking about.
Right. That's all that.
All right.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
their question. Sister Deborah, time
check.
Yes, the time is 9:09.
Oh.
All right. We like to say that we've ran
out of time and everybody that sent in a
question, please don't resubmit it.
Sister Deborah will take it, put it in
rotation, and we will address that
question next Wednesday.
So, until we all come together again, we
say be safe and be blessed.
Read your Bible. Keep the commandments
as brother James closes out.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come, thy will be done in
earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread, and
forgive us our debts as we forgive our
debtors. And lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil,
for thine is the kingdom
and the power and the glory forever. In
Jesus' name we pray. Amen.